[
    {
        "question": "A ripple counter's speed is limited by the propagation delay of:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "each flip-flop",
        "b": "all flip-flops and gates",
        "c": "the flip-flops only with gates",
        "d": "only circuit gates",
        "answer": "each flip-flop"
    },
    {
        "question": "To operate correctly, starting a ring counter requires:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "clearing all the flip-flops",
        "b": "presetting one flip-flop and clearing all the others",
        "c": "clearing one flip-flop and presetting all the others",
        "d": "presetting all the flip-flops",
        "answer": "presetting one flip-flop and clearing all the others"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of register would shift a complete binary number in one bit at a time and shift all the stored bits out one bit at a time?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "PIPO",
        "b": "SISO",
        "c": "SIPO",
        "d": "PISO",
        "answer": "SISO"
    },
    {
        "question": "Synchronous counters eliminate the delay problems encountered with asynchronous (ripple) counters because the:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "input clock pulses are applied only to the first and last stages",
        "b": "input clock pulses are applied only to the last stage",
        "c": "input clock pulses are not used to activate any of the counter stages",
        "d": "input clock pulses are applied simultaneously to each stage",
        "answer": "input clock pulses are applied simultaneously to each stage"
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the major drawbacks to the use of asynchronous counters is that:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "low-frequency applications are limited because of internal propagation delays",
        "b": "high-frequency applications are limited because of internal propagation delays",
        "c": "Asynchronous counters do not have major drawbacks and are suitable for use in high- and low-frequency counting applications.",
        "d": "Asynchronous counters do not have propagation delays, which limits their use in high-frequency applications.",
        "answer": "high-frequency applications are limited because of internal propagation delays"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of device may be used to interface a parallel data format with external equipment's serial format?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "key matrix",
        "b": "UART",
        "c": "memory chip",
        "d": "serial-in, parallel-out",
        "answer": "UART"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the output of a tri-state shift register is disabled, the output level is placed in a:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "float state",
        "b": "LOW state",
        "c": "high impedance state",
        "d": "float state and a high impedance state",
        "answer": "float state and a high impedance state"
    },
    {
        "question": "A comparison between ring and johnson counters indicates that:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "a ring counter has fewer flip-flops but requires more decoding circuitry",
        "b": "a ring counter has an inverted feedback path",
        "c": "a johnson counter has more flip-flops but less decoding circuitry",
        "d": "a johnson counter has an inverted feedback path",
        "answer": "a johnson counter has an inverted feedback path"
    },
    {
        "question": "A sequence of equally spaced timing pulses may be easily generated by which type of counter circuit?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "shift register sequencer",
        "b": "clock",
        "c": "johnson",
        "d": "binary",
        "answer": "shift register sequencer"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is meant by parallel-loading the register?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Shifting the data in all flip-flops simultaneously",
        "b": "Loading data in two of the flip-flops",
        "c": "Loading data in all four flip-flops at the same time",
        "d": "Momentarily disabling the synchronous SET and RESET inputs",
        "answer": "Loading data in all four flip-flops at the same time"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a shift register that will accept a parallel input and can shift data left or right called?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "tri-state",
        "b": "end around",
        "c": "bidirectional universal",
        "d": "conversion",
        "answer": "bidirectional universal"
    },
    {
        "question": "What happens to the parallel output word in an asynchronous binary down counter whenever a clock pulse occurs?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "The output word decreases by 1.",
        "b": "The output word decreases by 2.",
        "c": "The output word increases by 1.",
        "d": "The output word increases by 2.",
        "answer": "The output word decreases by 1."
    },
    {
        "question": "Mod-6 and mod-12 counters are most commonly used in:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "frequency counters",
        "b": "multiplexed displays",
        "c": "digital clocks",
        "d": "power consumption meters",
        "answer": "digital clocks"
    },
    {
        "question": "The serial-in, parallel-out shift register transfers data from one parallel data bus to another parallel data bus one bit at a time across a single line.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "A serial-in, serial-out shift register transfers data from one line of a parallel bus to another line one bit at a time.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "A ripple counter is an asynchronous counter.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "Counters are common components in digital clocks.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an asynchronous counter, each state is clocked by the same pulse.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "An asynchronous counter differs from a synchronous counter in the method of clocking.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "A multiplexed display circuit uses a technique called time division modulation.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "An asynchronous decade counter increases its value by ten for each clock pulse.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "A parallel-in, serial-out shift register enters all data bits simultaneously and transfers them out one bit at a time.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "The modulus (mod) of a counter is the same as its maximum count (N).\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "Asynchronous inputs will cause the flip-flop to respond immediately with regard to the clock input.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "Synchronous construction reduces the delay time of a counter to the delay of __________.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "all flip-flops and gates",
        "b": "a single flip-flop and a gate",
        "c": "all flip-flops and gates after a 3 count",
        "d": "a single gate",
        "answer": "a single flip-flop and a gate"
    },
    {
        "question": "A 4-bit PISO shift register that receives 4 bits of parallel data will shift to the ________ by ________ position(s) for each clock pulse.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "right, one",
        "b": "right, two",
        "c": "left, one",
        "d": "left, three",
        "answer": "right, one"
    },
    {
        "question": "To operate correctly, starting a ring counter requires __________.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "clearing one flip-flop and presetting all the others",
        "b": "clearing all the flip-flops",
        "c": "presetting one flip-flop and clearing all the others",
        "d": "presetting all the flip-flops",
        "answer": "presetting one flip-flop and clearing all the others"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to use a shift register as a counter, ________.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "the register's serial input is the counter input and the serial output is the counter output",
        "b": "the parallel inputs provide the input signal and the output signal is taken from the serial data output",
        "c": "a serial-in, serial-out register must be used",
        "d": "the serial output of the register is connected back to the serial input of the register",
        "answer": "the serial output of the register is connected back to the serial input of the register"
    },
    {
        "question": "A sequence of equally spaced timing pulses may be easily generated by a(n) __________.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "ring counter",
        "b": "johnson counter",
        "c": "binary up counter",
        "d": "ripple counter",
        "answer": "ring counter"
    },
    {
        "question": "Asynchronous counters are often called ________ counters.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "toggle",
        "b": "ripple",
        "c": "binary",
        "d": "flip-flop",
        "answer": "ripple"
    },
    {
        "question": "A _________ shift register can shift stored data either left or right.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "bidirectional",
        "b": "tri-state",
        "c": "universal",
        "d": "bidirectional universal",
        "answer": "bidirectional universal"
    },
    {
        "question": "The mod-10 counter is also referred to as a ________ counter.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "decade",
        "b": "strobing",
        "c": "ring",
        "d": "BCD",
        "answer": "decade"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ring and johnson counters are _______.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "asynchronous counters",
        "b": "synchronous counters",
        "c": "true binary counters",
        "d": "asynchronous and true binary counters",
        "answer": "synchronous counters"
    },
    {
        "question": "When two counters are cascaded, the overall mod number is equal to the __________ of their individual mod numbers.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "product",
        "b": "sum",
        "c": "log",
        "d": "reciprocal",
        "answer": "product"
    }
]